Faith is natural.
If something is natural, it means, with God.
If faith is natural, how do you receive that faith?
You do not need greater faith; you need to know the faithfulness and trustworthiness of God.
All you need to know is His faithfulness and trustworthiness, which you have received today.
"Be healed; be delivered; be set free" just like that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The moment you know God is faithful and reliable, your faith grows spontaneously.
With what you have seen now the faith will begin to increase in you.
Faith in God.
If you were a "zero" before seeing it, you realise that you begin to have that desire just naturally.
The moment you realise that God is faithful, reliable and trustworthy, your faith grows spontaneously.
The moment you realise that God is reliable, your find yourself trusting in Him.
That is faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to believe that you are a man and a woman of faith.
[Amen.]
If I am talking - let me see your hand.
Now, you know what faith is.
Someone might say, "Until I read the Bible from the Genesis to the end.
I have not been going to the church; I don't have faith.
I'm not a bishop, I'm not an evangelist. This is my first time coming to church." - No.
The issue of faith - faith is natural.
Listen; you do not need greater faith.
All you need is faithfulness and trustworthiness of God.
What you have been seeing now shows that God is reliable.
The moment you realise that God is faithful and reliable, you find that your faith grows naturally.
When you leave here, you will go to your bedroom, go on your knees and start praying.
And it has not been like that before.
It shows that you began to trust someone, who is wiser than you, more clever and more trustworthy than you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Something is growing now.
Something is growing.
Allow this to grow.
Anointing is the power of God.
The dividend of that power is what you have been seeing today.
The fruit of that power brings healing, salvation.
You see people getting healed, those who were crying for many years - just like that.
It was just a tap, not a slap.
If I slapped you you would feel it, "Man of God; you slapped me."
It was a tap.
There is a difference between tap and slap.
When you are fighting your neighbour - you slap
but when you tap - you tap a friend.
You slap your enemy.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If it was a slap; how many people I would be able to slap before getting tired?
Try to slap three people and see how would you feel.
You would get tired.
But you can tap a "trillion" people...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, if it was to be a traditional way of praying...
The traditional way of praying is this.
In the name of Jesus - be healed.
How many people could I do this to?
Even the voice, "In the name of Jesus".
You will get tired after ten minutes.
OK, let me try.
In the name of Jesus - you are healed, in Jesus' name.
In the name of Jesus - be healed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The person talking now Mr T.B. Joshua, not Prophet T.B. Joshua.
If it was a Prophet you would fly.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know I am a brother just like you.
It is not a Prophet who is talking now.
That is why I can touch you, "In the name of Jesus - be healed, in Jesus' name".
The method God has given me - look at it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Can you see?
It is just like that.
I do not know how many...
If you say I should now carry on... that you know what I am saying.
In the name of Jesus.
This is crazy.
It is the light we carry.
Once you light this candle you just touch.
You just say once, "In the name of Jesus" - you can do the whole...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you with me?
[Yes.]
If I now begin to say, "In the name of Jesus - be healed"...
It is only one call that Jesus heard out of three of my calls.
It is an unbelief that made us to call that name for several hours.
If you understand let me see your hand.
Now, "In the name of Jesus -
be healed."
How many times?
Five times.
If that healing comes it was only once Jesus heard our call.
Other four...
Because that came our of unbelief.
It is just like a human being; if I come to my mummy here now, "Mummy, mummy, mummy".
By the time mummy hears...
She would only hear once and say, "Yes! What do you want?"
She would not begin to answer me three times, "Mummy - yes. Mummy - yes. Mummy - yes".
Mother would say that something is wrong.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These are our challenges.
We have them a lot.
When it comes to the things of the spirit we are all babies.
We that are working for God; there is so much fights in the church because we do not understand ourselves.
The journey is so difficult; we don't understand.
You don't even know if a given person is a man of God.
You, man of God, you don't know if another man of God is a true one.
Can you see how difficult the journey is?
Are you with me?
[Yes.]
Let me give you a good example, come brothers.
Stand here.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are all ministers of God.
Could you believe that we may not even know that we are all ministers of God?
This one might not know that that one is a child of God like him, and he would be fighting him.
While this one too will continue to fight him...
Can you see?
What is the cause of this?
Why we don't even know ourselves?
Why?
It is because we don't know the strength of the ministry.
The strength of the ministry is not the crowd.
The strength of the ministry is not the number of people who worship
or the number of branches you have all over the world.
The strength of the ministry is the Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are many ministries of God that have five members and they are more anointed
then some ministries of God that have the biggest crowd in the world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The fact that they know you all over the world does not mean that you are the most anointed person.
The fact that your ministry is known all over the world does not mean
you are the most anointed person in the world.
Men of God - they don't know that.
The fact that your church is the biggest one in the world does not mean that you are the most anointed person.
There are some ministries of five members that are more anointed than you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The moment we know this, there would be no more fights.
We are running for members.
Everybody is trying to have the largest church in the world.
Everybody is trying to have branches everywhere.
Everybody is trying to have crowd, to be known.
Everybody is trying to be known all over the world.
This is the cause of fight.
We disregard the truth; the principle.
OK, if the ministry with the largest number of branches is the most anointed,
why The SCOAN is only in Ikotun-Egbe and it is known all over the world?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Here, in Ikotun-Egbe - a small village, there is only an arrow that links to the church,
and it is known all over the world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We refuse to advertise our program in any channel, apart from Emmanuel TV.
You will not see the signboards anywhere in the world.
When you come here you will not see signboards showing the direction to the church.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Think about that.
We will never look for you if you don't come to the church.
Nobody will want to know your house and begin to disturb you, "Why did you not come to church?
What is the problem. You have to come to church. OK?"
You don't need to collect any letter if you want to leave this ministry
because I had never asked you for any letter before you came here.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are talking about the strength of the ministry.
The strength of the ministry.
Once we know that - no problem.
Thank you brothers.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God has given us adverts.
God has given His ministry adverts.
Every living ministry has free adverts.
What you see about me is an advert to me.
When you leave here.
If you leave here today, tomorrow you go to the town and say, "That man is a devil, it is not a man of God" -
you are advertising me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Or tomorrow you just leave here and say, "That church - don't go there. They used to tie people down.
It is a bad church."
You are indirectly advertising me.
Because the people you are telling it to will want to confirm if they truly tie people down.
By the time they come and find out that people are not tied down - they become members.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I have been using this advert for many years.
People don't know.
This is why I don't have sign posts.
No boards.
You cannot see signposts outside.
This an advert God has been giving me for past 30 years.
God said, "Don't have any signposts, signboards. People will advertise your ministry to the world."
Free of charge.
Thank you for your adverts.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, you too; leave the truth to defend itself.
Let people advertise you.
Don't fight, whatever people say about you.
If truly you are genuine, whether they condemn you or spoil your name - it is for your good.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take your time.
Just ask yourself what brought you here.
You will know that what people had said about me brought you here.
You are here to confirm.
And that confirmation will lead you to our friendship.
We will soon become friends.
Don't fight.
Take it easy.
What people say about your business,
what people say about your family,
what people say about your life out there - is for your good.
If truly you are sent by God it will turn around to favour you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service